ALICIA N. GORTON

Sacramento, CA 95834

Phone: 217-377-7697 | Email: aliciagorton17@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alicia-gorton | GitHub: github.com/aliciagorton | Portfolio: aliciagorton.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a MERN focus. Passionate to merge professional background in healthcare with technology. Adept communicator, organizer, and problem solver. Confident in ability to utilize learned skills and ability to strengthen any team. Recently graduated from UC Davis with a certificate in Web Development. Expert in customer service and client satisfaction. Trained at prioritizing tasks, being efficient with time and dealing in high stress environments. Aim to build better software experiences, driven to make a difference, motivated to work as part of a team to diagnose and solve complex problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Handlebars

Libraries / Tools: Node.js, MongoDB, Express, MySQL, NoSQL, Git, GitHub, React.js, React, API's, Caches, Cookies, Local Storage,

Responsive Design, SASS, Bootstrap, User Authentication, Material UI, Security and Session Storage

Competencies/Other: Heroku, Webpack, Data Structures, Data Analysis, Data Science, Algorithms, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Excel,

Microsoft Powerpoint

PROJECTS

Leet | Code: http://bit.ly/3oO9j6B | Live: https://bit.ly/3sfFr51

Leet is a web application where the user creates a profile, from there they can auto-populate PDF's. Leet offers already templated PDF's or the ability for a user to upload their own.

- Led a team of 4 to design, develop, and debug, and deploy our web application
- Maintained gitflow workflow for application, reviewed all pull requests from team to ensure code quality and consistency.
- Developed user credentials, authorization through passport, and deployed the web application to Heroku
- Front End developer using React, designed user interface, page layouts and components, used redux, and react hooks.
- Built using React.js, Passport, Express, Node.js, MongoDBs, Material UI, third-party APIs, and JavaScript.

Kuma | Code: bit.ly/3mmBBDA | Live: bit.ly/3mkn6A1

Kuma is a web application that allows people to create profiles for their pets and compare traits with other members' pets to find playdates for them while also meeting new people with similar interests.

- Collaborated with a team of 3 developers for all phases of the development life cycle, focusing on coding, testing, and debugging.
- Using Agile methodologies and participated in weekly SCRUM meetings remotely using Zoom.
- Developed user credentials, web sessions and relational databases.
- Front End developer designed user interface, page layouts and page designs.
- Built using Sequelize, Passport, Express, Node.js, Handlebars, MySQL, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.

Chuck Norris Fan Page | Code: bit.ly/3jtaVik | Live: bit.ly/34rx9wV

Chuck Norris "Fan Page" with retro throwback twist, reminiscent of early web experiences and design.

- Worked with a team of 3 to develop, debug merging conflicts, and deployment with Git.
- Remotely organized with weekly SCRUM meetings using Slack and Zoom.
- Developed using DOM, fetch requests with APIs and creating event listeners to respond to user interactivity.
- Contribution focused on javascript, writing functions, creating responsive events and utilizing API's.
- Built using two server-side APIs, a third-party API, Javascript, and Bulma.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Registered Behavioral Technician (RBT)

October 2019 - September 2020

Maxium Health Services Sacramento, CA

Worked in multiple environments to provide ABA therapy; including homes and in schools. Interpreted and analyzed data to develop strategies for the best care possible and fostered strong relationships with families involved.

- Recommended by direct supervisor to apply for promotions within the company. Finalist in process when pandemic eliminated the role.
- Accomplished high goal achievements by meeting industry standard of 80% or higher over consecutive therapy sessions for every new goal.
- Collaborated with a team of 3-4 to develop, plan, and implement child's goals.
- Recognized by management for diligent documentation, self-sufficient problem solving, and being responsive to all parties involved.

Registered Behavioral Technician (RBT)

June 2019 - October 2020

Intercare Therapy Inc.

Sacramento, CA

On a team that spearheaded the first rollout of online documentation in the company.

- Worked cross-functionally with web application developers to give perspective from the field.
- Passed exam for the state of California to become a Registered Behavioral Technician achieving over 80% and completing over 120 hours with direct coaching.

Achieved goals weekly by meeting or surpassing the company standard of 85% or higher over consecutive therapy sessions.

Behavioral Technician May 2018 - May 2019

Comprehensive Early Autism Services

Chicago, IL

Provided ABA therapy to children with autism, in multiple settings such as community, school, and home environments.

Responsibilities included detailed documentation, coaching for teachers, and ability to transmit important information to all parties. Learned invaluable de-escalation and crisis prevention techniques.

- Achieved high success rate with implementation of each goal set for my clients
- Met success rate of 80% or higher for two consecutive therapy sessions.
- Passed CPI (crisis prevention courses), in order to work on more challenging cases.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of California at Davis, CA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Science in Psychology: University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign, IL

A breadth and depth in the study of human and animal behavior. Emphasis on statistical analysis, research techniques and methodologies. An understanding in the biological process of behavior.

Licensed Practical Nurse: Parkland College, Champaign, IL

An accredited program, focused on teaching transferable skills through long-term care facilities, clinics, and hospitals. Licensed 2012